# Bawantha Rajapaksha

Software Engineer

bawwa.16@cse.mrt.ac.lk • +94771641667

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bawantha-rajapaksha/ • https://github.com/bawantha/ • https://stackover-flow.com/users/8135721/bawantha

https://bawantha.github.io/

## **Summary**

Current SE at Codegen UK, 2 years experience full stack developer. doing freelancing for 4 years. The mobile development stack is the core strength. Interested in devising a better problem solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

#### **Skills**

Ionic • Android • iOS • sqllite • AWS (Amazon Web Services) • Spring Boot • Flutter • Angular

## **Work Experience**

Sofware Enginner Mar 2021 – present

Codegen International • Full-time

Remote

#### Technologies: Spring boot • Flutter • Ionic • Angular • React Native

- · Contributing to Ionic mobile app related to healthcare,
- created MVC flutter app for with Firebase auth and SQLite drift database.
- · Maintaining full mobile app cycle for android and iOS with CI/CD pipelines using Fastlane + Gitlab
- Backend development with Springboot. deployment with Kubernetes.
- Angular frontend web app development relates to finance.
- · WordPress plugin development related to marketing.

## **Mobile Application Developer**

Sep 2022 – present

Kvickk AB • Part-time

Remote

Technologies: AWS (Amazon Web Services) • Android studio • Figma • Flutter/dart • iOS

Developing mobile app for transportation indrustry

Mobile Developer Jan 2021 - Jul 2021 • 6 mos

Preventa Medical • Contract

Remote

#### Technologies: Flutter • Firebase • Full Stack

- Worked on converting an existing web app to a fully functional flutter web app.
- Proposed best practices of flutter and maintaining a clean + clear + simple flutter web app

Freelance developer Mar 2020 – present

Fiverr • Freelance

Remote

#### Technologies: Flask • Flutter • WordPress • Android • iOS

- Makeup shopping mobile app with image processing
- SMS automation mobile application
- · Flight training mobile application
- · Medicine booking app with pharmacy

## **Trainee Software Enginner**

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019 • 6 mos

Mitra Innovations • Internship

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

#### Technologies: Express JS • Flask • JavaScript • PostgreSQL • Python

- Contributed to building rapid applications using Flask with Flask app builder and using PostgreSQL database with Pgadmin4.
- Created collective marketing platform with Raspberry PI using captive portals
- Contributed to customizing flask big data visualize platform Apache superset

## **Projects**

## **Flutter Widget Catcher**

Mar 2022 - present

#### **Technologies: JavaScript**

Sometimes copying the flutter widget from the web can be tricky. Because finding correct closing parenthesis might be quite cumbersome. Flutter widget catcher is a useful widget to copy Flutter Widgets.

## **Payhere Payment Gateway for Flutter**

Jan 2000 - Mar 2020 • 20 yrs 2 mos

#### Technologies: Java • Dart/flutter

At that time there was no way to collect payment from Payhere (payhere.lk) using Flutter so I decided to create a plugin that would help anyone to collect payment using the Payhere payment gateway.

<u>Thel - SL fuel Finder</u> May 2022 – present

1 coworker

#### Technologies: Flutter/dart • Android • Google Cloud Platform • Firebase

We had a fuel shortage in our country there were long queues near fuel stations. I decided to create this app, this will help people to find fuel availability at filling stations in Sri Lanka.

Hand Wash Reminder Nov 2019 − Jan 2020 • 2 mos

#### Technologies: Flutter • Firebase

Covid -19 was a new and life-threatening virus. Health authorities always suggest keeping clean hands and wash them regularly, So I decided to create this app, which will remind people to wash their hands regularly.

## **Medicare Mobile application**

Jan 2022 - present

3 coworkers

## Technologies: Flutter/dart

Patients and Doctors can share lab reports, prescriptions, and other health-related visitation-related measurements via this application.built using Flutter with Firebase and SQLite DB

#### **Educations**

#### Bachelor's degree: Computer Science and Engineering.

Jan 2016 - May 2021 • 5 yrs 4 mos

University of Moratuwa

Colombo, Sri Lanka Grade/GPA: 3.28

## High school diploma: IT

lan 2015 - Oct 2015 • 9 mos

Esoft Metro Campus Colombo, Sri Lanka

## Languages

**English** (Professional working proficiency)